Still hiding, Fatso?
肥狗 躲了这么久?
I'm busting you no matter what.
我抓不到你 难以交差
Have I ever busted the wrong guy?
我做警察这么久 有没有抓错人?
I'll leave the answer to the judge.
这个问题我由法官回答
My duty as a cop...
我的职责就是...
is to catch thieves.
警察抓贼
- Four fives. - Open!
- 四个五 - 开!
- Yeah! Drink! - I gotta win.
- 有 饮! - 不好不算数
Let's guess again. One bottle.
再猜 再猜 猜这瓶
Seven sixes? All of a kind again?
七个六? 你又围骰吗?
You know how to play or not?
你会不会玩?
Waiter, show her the instruction book.
侍应 拿说明书给她看看
Let me introduce my brother. Tiger. Sam.
给你介绍我的弟弟 阿虎 山哥
- Nice to meet you, Sam! - Nice to meet you!
- 山哥你好! - 你好!
You sweat a lot.
你汗水真多
That's my real brother, Archer.
那是我的亲大哥 渣哥
I got lots of inventory.
我有很多货
I have men everywhere but you want it all.
海陆空都有人负责 你却要全盘接收
You're going to Vietnam.
你要去越南
The three of us can take care of this.
去越南当然是由我们三兄弟去办
Who knows better than us?
有谁会比我们熟?
We were from Vietnam.
我们是越南来的
Your splitting ratio
你说怎么分帐就怎么分
is fine by me.
没什么好说的
Lost again.
又输了
No, No. One more time.
不好 不好 再来
Four ones. One bottle.
四个一 猜整瓶 不管了
Four ones?
四个一?
- You sure you have them? - I bloody sure do.
- 你有没有呀? - 你老娘就没有
Police inspection. Lights on.
警察查牌 开灯
Stand over there!
站一边!
You! Step forward!
你 出来!
I did toss the bottle.
那玻璃瓶是我扔的
So what?
又如何?
Excuse me... I'm sorry...
不好意思...不好意思...
On Jan 2, 1996,
一九九六年 一月二日
you intentionally injured
旺角新填地街查牌行动中
a suspect in Mongkok,
你蓄意伤人
fracturing his hipbone
疑犯盘骨位置骨裂
and 3 ribs.
断了三节肋骨 住院两个月
Do you admit?
你认不认?
On Feb 17, 1996,
一九九六年 二月十七日
during an anti-Triad operation on Temple Street,
油麻地庙街反黑行动
you injured another suspect intentionally,
你又再蓄意伤人
causing serious head concussion
疑犯头部严重受伤
and permanent anosmia.
经医生诊断 永远失去味觉
Do you admit?
你认不认!
- In 1996... - Enough! I admit to it all.
- 一九九六年... - 别说了 我认
During the first half of this year alone,
只是今年上半年
you had an average of 14 operations a month
你平均每个月有十四次行动
and you hurt an average of 2.8 people each time.
每次行动平均伤人2.8个
You already broke last year's record in half a year.
半年 你已经破了去年的纪录
What's wrong with cops busting thieves?
差人抓贼有什么问题
It's my turn to complain.
现在要投诉的人是我
Are you guys busting thieves or cops?
究竟你们是抓贼 还是抓警察
I know you're an excellent officer, Inspector Ma.
马督察 我知道你是一个出色的警员
You also have the highest crime detection rate.
破案率亦是全警队最高的
But beware of your attitude,
但我想提醒你
ways and means.
一定要注意你的态度和办案手法
I don't see any problems with them!
我觉得没有问题
OK, you can go.
好 你可以出去
I've been here
我算过了 由我入房到现在
for a full hour.
你说了整整一个小时
Could have cracked a case outside already.
说不定足够我在外面破一宗案子
You better evaluate
你们是不是该检讨一下
your law enforcement standards.
你们的执法标准?
Don't waste everybody's time.
以免大家浪费时间
Good!
好!
Give me 50 grand.
给我五万 老娘
Such a high stake! You'll lose.
跟我玩也玩得那么大 你输定了!
Tiger.
虎哥...
That's not the way to play golf.
高尔夫球并不是这样打的
It's not kung fu. Stand firm.
你以为打功夫吗? 扎实马步的
I'll teach you, ok?
我教你打
It's very simple. Grab the club.
其实好简单 随便拿起球杆
Keep feet and shoulders straight and parallel.
然后要双脚和肩膊垂直平排
Look far ahead and then at your ball.
然后望向远方 再望你的球
Swing hard.
再大力挥出
This is just a counter-example.
这个是错误示范
Next time! Next time!
下一次...
Something seems wrong, Archer.
渣哥 好像有不妥
Don't say anything.
别说了
My friends here are clean.
我这里有几个朋友不碰这东西的
Go now!
你们先走!
I asked you to transport goods to Vietnam.
叫你运东西到越南
But it's always too windy or rainy for you.
你不是说刮风就是下雨
2 months already! Planning a trip to the moon?
兄弟 两个多月了 现在去月球吗?
You trying to mess with me?
是不是耍花样?
No man, but bad weather is quite natural.
不是 大风大浪当然有
I didn't even blame you
我还未说你
for the bad luck.
这么倒霉 船沉了都赖你
I have 80M there. Get it back and we're quits.
那里有八千万 拿回来就扯平
Should've told me earlier. I'll courier it for you.
你早点说嘛 我帮你速递
It only takes a couple of days by plane.
坐飞机两三天就到了
Who would've used a boat? Sure it takes weeks.
现在坐船吗? 当然要等两三个星期
You better wait quietly at home!
你回家慢慢等吧!
What did you say?
你说什么!
Stay cool or I'll beat you up.
你千万不要乱来 再来 我会打死你
You threatening me? Who you think you are?
你吓我 你是谁啊
You're the boss but you can't call the shot?
现在做老大的拿不出主意
You need your henchman. Ask Tony to come out.
要手下出来吗 叫Tony出来
Shit!
老娘!
That's how we run things here.
我们做事 就是这样
Is it really necessary to do this in public?
要不要在大庭广众做这种动作?
Just putting on sun block!
擦太阳油啊
You trying to get even or what?
你要不要这样子 报仇啊?
Wait for me first.
先等我再说
You always end up arguing.
每次谈都吵架
Latte!
Latte啊!
Ask him to cut the crap. He could've busted me.
你叫他少装酷 带队捉人就捉人
Why he always had to fight?
总要跟人打
Even though I know you're good at it.
我知道你很会打了
You called me for help
每次有事你就找我
and I gave you a hand.
你找我 我当然要照顾你
Now things got out of hand
弄出麻烦 你就怪我
and you're blaming me.
我怎么工作啊!
Stop yelling! You naked,
你这个肌肉人还吵?
hunky piece of meat!
成天脱了衣服撅着屁股
And you hurt my wrist so badly.
还弄得我的手这么痛
The doctor said there might be complications.
医生说以后还有后遗症
Last time you threw a bottle of wine at me.
你上次整瓶酒泼过来
I would've blown your cover
如果我不动手
if I hadn't reacted.
所有人都知道我们是串通的
And you fought back. Remember?
你还手啊 你不记得了!
I would've lost face
你一巴掌打我啊 我不还手?
if I hadn't fought back.
怎出来混?
Lost face? You're a cop! Lost face?
你出来混 你警察来的 出来混
You want a loudspeaker, you dumbo?
给你咪高峰好不好 这么大声 笨蛋
You're partners. You shouldn't have hit him so hard.
大家都是自已人 你出手不该那么重
Knowing his temper, you shouldn't have provoked him.
你也是的 明知道他火爆还要惹他
Why made such a mess?
你干嘛搞得那么大
When I'm duped, you said we're partners.
骗我时 就说是一起干
But he can play the model every day.
他就整天装模特儿
You two want me to be a snitch till when?
你们俩想我做卧底做到什么时候?
Bygones are bygones.
别说从前了 老老实实
Who's leading whom anyway?
现在是谁管谁?
- Not this again! - Not what?
- 又来这个! - 来哪个?
Cops have regulations.
警察有制度的
Stop arguing. You might not be partners anymore.
别吵了 你们俩以后可能不用再合作
Really?
那么好?
The verdict is out.
Capo那边出了裁决
You still lead.
你还是做领袖
Report to the Police Band next week.
下个星期到银乐队报到
No way! They've gone too far!
不是吧 不用那么绝情!
As you just said, cops have regulations.
你也会说 警察部有制度的
I'm appealing!
我要上诉!
Keep it up!
继续工作 看你了!
Ditto!
彼此彼此!
We can't think too much. Just go ahead!
做人不能算那么多 想做就做
If we're destined to die, so be it!
死就死吧 反正也活够本了!
What's wrong with you? You got it wrong 4 times!
你怎么吹的! 吹四次就错四次!
How so?
你哪一只耳朵听到我错?
The E-flat
第十二个小节
after the sextuplet on the 12th bar.
六连音后面那个E降音
We heard nothing.
我们什么也都听不到
Just you yelling.
只听到你在骂人
Be serious! We are cops.
我们做警察是不是要认真点
If you wanna play, form your own band.
你们要去玩 就去组乐队
You can't expect everyone to be like you.
不是每个人都要像你才对 马长官
- You dare to talk back... - You are definitely wrong!
- 还顶嘴... - 你们一定是错!
When a cop errs, he either hurts others
警察做错事 要不害死人
or he hurts himself. Do yourjob well.
要不害死自已 下点心机做好这份工
Mom, I'm busy.
妈 我在工作
I won't bother you.
我知道你在忙
I'm going back to my hometown.
我不阻你 我回乡下了
I'll go with you when I have time.
等我有空跟你一起回去
I did wait.
我有等
I waited till my friend there died.
等到潮洲婆也死了
If I'm happy there,
我去上香 要是住得高兴
I probably won't come back.
我大概不会回来
Mom, don't!
不要吧 妈...
I'll be bored here all by myself.
我一个人在这里很闷
You worry about me, yet you have no time for me.
要你整天担心 你又没有空理我
Be careful.
小心点
Don't risk your life catching thieves.
抓贼不用这么拚命的
What's most important to a man?
做人最重要的是什么?
Preserving life. Without life, how can you be a man?
是保住性命 命都没有了 如何做人
Be careful. I gotta go.
小心点 我走了
We're all trying to make a living here.
大家都是混饭吃
You swiped Sam's goods.
你们吞掉阿山的货
He came here to talk but you wanted him dead.
他找你们谈 你们还揍他
Now you ask us to stay out of the way?
你现在叫我们不要管 为什么不管?
Sam has to go.
阿山一定要消失
You don't wanna get hurt by accident, do you?
到时把你们牵扯进去就不太好
If you back off, nothing will happen.
你们不管 就没有事
Without you three, nothing will happen.
没有你三个 就什么事都不会发生
You better not mess up my place.
你们最好不要搅乱我的地方
We took you in when you were refugees.
没有我们收留你 你们还在海上漂浮
We were stuck in the refugee camp
我们一家人困在白石难民营
like prisoners.
跟坐监没有分别
Why did we riot?
为什么会暴动
Because we wanted our own home.
因为我们要有自已的家
If anyone wants us to leave today,
如果今天还有人不想我们留下来
they have to fight us.
我们就要打
- Brother! - How's the talk?
- 大哥! - 怎样 谈到哪里
Didn't work?
不行吗?
No, we're still talking.
不 不是谈不拢 是还未谈妥
Don't move yet, or there's no point talking anymore.
你不要动手 杀死了他还怎么谈?
Don't play games, you three.
你们三兄弟不要在这里耍花样
- Forget it. Let's move. - Wait.
- 不谈了 动手 - 等等
I'll let you talk to him.
我给你跟他说
Your wife took your son
四眼 你老婆那么早
to school so early.
就带你的儿子上学
It would be a pity if he's dead.
死了真是可惜
You're buffing me.
你这即是威胁我
Of course. Thought I'd buy you breakfast?
我当然是威胁你 难道请你吃早餐
I don't wanna hurt each other's feelings either.
我也不想伤害大家的感情
If you can talk, we can cooperate in the future.
有商量的话 将来还有很多合作机会
The woman in red with the child,
穿红衣那一个四眼女人
both wearing glasses.
带住一四眼小孩
He looks kind of dumb.
傻傻的那个
When I ask you to dash toward them,
一会儿我叫你撞过去
you go ahead.
你就一鼓劲儿撞过去
OK!
好!
Hurry up. Made up your mind yet?
快点 想好了没有
Your son is almost near the door.
你的四眼儿子快到门口了
I didn't hear an answer.
我听不到有人答我
I'll stay out of Sam's business.
阿山的事我不管
Louder, or he can't hear.
你这么小声 他听不到
I'll stay out of Sam's business.
阿山的事我不管
You stand down, I stand down.
你别乱来 我就什么都不知道
Archer... Hero.
阿渣...大侠
Let's get together and have fun some time. We're buddies.
有空一块儿去玩 大家都是朋友
Glad that you said that.
你会这么说就好
Let's have breakfast. Don't waste it.
吃早餐 买了不吃 是不是不赏面?
- Dash forward. - OK.
- 冲过去 - 哦
Take a turn.
拐弯!
Are you a dog? So obedient.
你是狗吗 这么听话的
He asked you to dash and you did. It's dangerous.
叫你冲过去就冲过去 会死人的
So cruel.
你真残忍
I rented a place tonight to celebrate your birthday.
今晚我租了一个地方庆祝你生日
I'm meeting a friend.
我约了朋友了
- What? You have friends? - Sure!
- 什么? 你都有朋友? - 有!
- Have fun! - Thanks, Archer.
- 玩得高兴点 - 多谢渣哥!
Lynn.
琳琳
Of course it's me. You free? Come over.
当然是我 有空吗? 来我家
Why are you cursing me?
你在说什么呀? 你没事咒我干嘛?
Auntie May, can I talk to your daughter?
媚姨 我想找你的女儿
What?
什么?
She's dead?
死了?
I'm so sorry!
不好意思!
Vivien, it's Wilson.
慧慧 华生
What?
什么事?
Nothing, it's my birthday today.
没什么 今天我生日
Don't say it's none of your business.
你不要说与你无关
Actually I won
其实我今天中了六合彩
the lottery today...
打算分你一份
- Judy, please. - Happy Birthday!
- 秋堤在吗? - 生日快乐
Thank you...
多谢...
Are you off work already?
你下班了没有?
Not yet. I'll drop by your place later.
还没 下班去你那边
OK, bye!
好 再见
Bye.
再见
Long time no see.
好久没见
Not that long. Only half a year!
有多久? 才半年而已!
Been to Vietnam lately?
最近有没有去越南?
Be careful if you're going there.
我跟你说 你去的话要小心点
Don't be caught by the cops.
小心给那边警察抓住
They put people away for eating Pho?
去越南吃越南河粉而已 也要坐牢?
You said you wouldn't sell liquor but you are now.
你说过不卖酒 现在又在卖酒
You think I like selling liquor?
你以为我喜欢卖酒吗?
What else can I do?
不卖酒我还可以做什么 难道...
A whore?
你想我做妓女吗?
Don't say that. There're many ways to fame.
你不要这么说 行行出状元嘛
You know this Blue Girl.
好像你也认识蓝妹
She also sold liquor. Now she has her own brand.
都是卖酒 卖到一个牌子回来
How about Carlsberg?
那加士伯呢?
Carl used to sell burgers
他就可怜了
before he sold beer.
老得像一个阿伯才开始做酒
That's why his brand is called Carlsberg.
要不然 也不会叫加士伯
How about mine?
那我这个呢?
So don't say we have no future.
所以你别说这一行没有前途
Johnny Walker used to walk here,
他就是走着走着
there, everywhere.
找到JohnnyWaIker回来做
I'll take a shower. I'll leave on my own later.
一会儿我自已走 我先洗澡
- Something's up, Tiger? - You bet!
- 虎哥 有状况? - 你干不了的
Where we going later?
一会儿去哪?
- Picnic in the suburbs! - OK!
- 我要去郊外野餐! - 好!
Take my daughter first!
带女儿先走!
- Cops! Get into the car! - Shit!
- 有警察! 上车! - 你老娘!
You can be discharged any time.
你随时可以出院
If you wanna fight, I won't cut you slack.
要打的话 我不会放过你
If you wanna die, don't get me involved.
要死就走远点 不要烦我
I wanna testify.
我要做污点证人
Come in!
进来!
Inspector Wong, we brought a perp in.
黄长官 带了一个犯人回来
It hurts, Inspector Wong.
痛啊 黄长官
Get me something to drink. It's so hot.
找人给我一杯饮料 热得很
Sam has squealed on Tony.
阿山将Tony的事全吐出来了
That's great. Take him in!
这就行 快点抓人吧!
We need to plan our deployment.
还要等部署
Those guys are fierce.
那班人很凶
You'll die if they find out.
要是暴露了 第一个死的就是你
I know that. I'm more scared than you.
我知道 我比你还害怕
Don't tell me you're leading the operation!
黄长官 你不要告诉我是你带队
Relax.
你放心 不是我带队
Those Viets are not my turf.
我不负责越南人这宗案
Call back the most ferocious officer.
叫警队最英勇最威猛那个回来
The Force needs him urgently.
现在警队极之需要他
It's you who need him the most.
是你最需要他
Inspector Wong!
黄长官!
Shut the door!
快点关门!
What's with you?
你干什么?
Why you kept the door open for so long?
找死吗 开门开那么久!
It's OK.
今次没事的了
Let me know if anything goes wrong.
总之有事就出声
It's fine, or I wouldn't have called you back.
行了 要不然我也不会叫你回来
Get this over with quickly
合作一点 尽快办妥这宗案
and we'll go for a dip. All right?
一起游泳 好吗?
- Sure. - Yes, officer.
- 好 - 是的 长官
Put on your helmet.
先带头套...
- Let me finish my cig first. - Drop your cig...
- 抽完这支烟才带吧 - 不要抽烟罢
or you won't find a gal.
弄到你的脸 泡不到女孩
Put on your helmet first!
先带头套
Bastard!
臭小子
Inspector Wong, look at him!
黄长官 他耍花样!
Beat him up!
拉他出去打吧
It's almost 1997.
都快九七回归了
Stop horsing around.
你们俩认真点吧 还嚷着玩
It's their mom's birthday tonight.
今晚他们的妈妈生日
They'll show up.
到时他们三个一定出现
Help me clear the scene first.
你先帮我清理现场
We need you to assist
四眼 越南人的事
in the Viets' case.
我想请你回去协助调查
OK!
好!
Wilson!
华生哥!
Wilson...
华生哥...
Have a bite. It's very yummy.
来 吃一口 真的很香
- Try it! - Auntie.
- 你尝尝 尝一口! - 伯母
Many happy returns!
恭祝你福如东海 寿比南山
May you be younger and prettier!
今年比去年漂亮 年年都青春
Thank you!
谢谢...
No appetite?
伯母 今天胃口好不好?
Don't talk to her. She won't eat.
不要逗她说话 她不肯吃了
- Gotta go! - OK.
- 走开 - 好
Enjoy your meal, Auntie.
伯母 你慢慢吃
Call again if you don't get a reply.
不回电话就继续打 不用我教吧
What time is it? Still not a soul.
现在几点了? 一个人也没有
- Have a bite! - Shit! Let's go!
- 吃一口! - 你妈的 去吧!
Have a bite!
吃一口!
Tiger!
阿虎!
Come over!
过来
You're too loud! You scared Mom.
你这大嗓门吓得妈不吃东西了
Kneel down!
跪下来
Say sorry to Mom.
跟妈妈道歉
Mom! Please eat something.
妈! 你吃东西吧
Everybody is here.
齐人了
So nobody's
没人去见阿渣
going to Archer's Mom's birthday?
谁给他们老母亲做大寿?
Have a bite.
吃一口吧
Come on.
来
Have a bite.
吃吧
It's very yummy.
妈 好吃的
I'll order
你不喜欢吃这些?
something else for you.
叫另外一些东西给你吃
Sea cucumber?
海参?
Abalone?
鲍鱼?
You don't like this? How about bird's nest?
你不喜欢吃这个? 那我叫燕窝给你吃
Shark fin!
鱼翅!
Brother, we have a situation!
哥 出事了!
What situation can be worse than Mom not eating?
有什么事比妈不吃饭更重要?
Please eat.
吃吧
Tiger, feed Mom.
阿虎! 喂妈吃
Let's start working!
开工了
Stay here tonight. Someone will take care of you.
今晚...留下来 有人会招呼你们
Good luck with the bust, Inspector Ma.
最重要抓到人 马长官
Come on.
来
Please eat.
吃吧
You don't like the food in this restaurant.
妈 这里的东西不合你口味
I can take you to another one. OK?
我带你去另一间吃 好不好?
Tiger!
阿虎!
- Wilson! Come here. - Coming.
- 华生! 过来 - 来
- Hurry up! - OK!
- 快点 - 好!
Captain!
部长!
You have a car? What make? Where's it parked?
你有没有开车? 开什么车 停在哪?
So?
怎样?
Take the cash.
Tony 拿钱
I drive Mom first. See you at the pier.
我先带妈妈走 码头见
Got it!
收到!
Where we going?
去哪 Tony哥?
To the warehouse.
去仓库
What's wrong?
二哥 什么事?
I saw nobody.
我那时都看不到人
How do I know when he left?
怎知道他几点钟离开!
Saw anyone suspicious?
有没有见到可疑人物?
- Inspector Ma! - How's his situation?
- 马长官! - 情况怎么样?
Still breathing. The ambulance is on its way.
有呼吸 救护车正赶来
- Cindy... - Yes!
-小樱... - 是!
Check his license plate number.
调查他的车牌号码
Yang, you stay behind and wrap things up.
杨仔 你留下来收拾手尾
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
Hello.
喂
Where are you? I'm at your door.
你在哪? 我在你家门口
I'm busy. I'll call you back.
我在忙 一会儿打给你
Should I wait for you at your place tonight?
要不 我今晚在你家等你
Not tonight.
今晚不行
I'll cut you a key...next time. Bye.
我配了你一条锁匙...下次给你 再见
- Stop talking on the phone! - Sorry.
- 不要打电话好不好! - 对不起
The target is
大炮 目标车辆分别是
a dark green Mazda MPV.
深绿色"万事得 ,MPV
License plate JL2933.
车牌JL2933
The other is a crimson Acura.
另外枣红色"极品 ,汽车
DE3654.
车牌DE3654
Give me a hand.
帮忙啊
Did you lock the door, Tiger?
虎哥 有没有锁门?
You're right!
对了!
I'll go lock it. You get in first.
我去锁 你们先上车
They are packing to flee. Talk later.
他们拿了钱准备走 再联络
Let's go, Tony
行了 Tony哥
- Is it locked? - Yes!
- 锁了没有? - 锁了!
Sit at the back!
坐后面!
OK!
好!
That one looks like it.
是那辆车
Wilson, hand me your phone.
华生 把你的电话给我
Tony!
Tony哥!
Sit tight, Mom
妈 坐好
Slow down!
不要开那么快!
Pull over! I say pull over!
停车 停车! 我叫你停车
Mom, sit tight!
妈 坐稳!
It's headed towards Chai Wan.
嘉辉 柴湾方向
- Hang in there. - I wanna puke.
- 没事嘛 撑住 - 我要吐
Puke there.
吐进去...吐进去就行
It's OK. Just puke.
没事的 吐吧
It's made a turn towards an industrial building.
转了去工厂大厦
Get off!
下车!
We're headed toward the pier.
我们正赶往码头
Go see what happened.
下车看看
Are you all right, buddy?
老友 你没事吗?
- How's Wilson? - Inspector Wong!
- 华生怎么样? - 黄长官
Dunno yet. Doctors are operating on him.
还不知道 正在抢救
That means he will be OK. Stay calm.
有的救即是没有事 镇定点
What's with you? Are you crazy?
干什么 你疯了
If anything happens to Wilson,
死警察 华生有什么事
you have to pay.
我绝不会放过你们
- What's with you? - None of your business.
- 你干什么? - 关你什么事
You must be Judy.
你叫秋堤吧
I can arrest you for hitting a cop.
你打警察 我可以立即拘捕你
- So what if you're a cop? - Wilson is my partner.
- 警察很了不起吗 - 华生是我的拍档
He's also a cop.
他也是警察
What you in for? Triad?
犯了什么? 黑社会?
No, I'm no Triad.
不是 我不是黑社会
Then follow me...
不是 那跟我...
Call me Archer.
叫声渣哥 叫吧
Archer.
渣哥!
Did you see your three sons beat people up?
你有没有见到你三个儿子打人?
I have three sons?
我有三个儿子?
He has disappeared.
不见了
Sir, can you call the police for me?
先生 你帮我报警好吗?
I need to call the police.
先生 你帮我报警
My son has disappeared.
我的儿子不见了
No one will take care of her,
这段时间不会有人看她了
now or ever.
或者以后都没有
Watch over her. She might go astray.
麻烦你好好照顾婆婆 她会周围跑的
It's my birthday. I'm 80 today. Come earlier.
我生日啊...八十岁...早点到
I'm 80. I'm 80.
我八十岁...八十岁...
Archer Sin, there's enough evidence that
冼伟查 有充份证据指出
from 1992 to Feb 1997, you've been involved in
你由1992年至1997年2月期间
smuggling, infliction of injury
进行一连串走私、严重伤人
and Triad activities.
及黑社会活动
You're hereby thus charged. Do you confess?
现在正式起诉你 你认不认罪?
No, sir.
不 长官
The court is
案件押后至本年五月
adjourned till May.
交付北九龙裁判法院审理
Meanwhile, turn over your travel documents.
这段期间 你要交出你的旅游证件
No travel outside Hong Kong. No bail.
不准出境 不准保释
All your assets will be frozen
你所有资金将会暂时被冻结
till the case is closed.
直至案件审结为止
You're blaming all this on me. Sure you can do it?
全算在我身上 你能不能把我告倒?
Go!
走!
Hands off!
放手 摸来摸去
- Or I'll sue you for sexual harassment. - Go!
- 我告你非礼 - 走吧!
I almost can't catch up with you!
我快追不到你!
I'll slow down a bit for you, ok?
那我慢一点迁就你 好不好?
Slowly. You'll get used to it slowly.
慢慢来 慢慢就惯了
Of course slowly. One of my feet is crippled.
当然慢了 一只脚废了 当然不惯
Everything has been well arranged.
跟你安排好了
You're transferred to Admin. Effective next week.
转做文职 下星期上班
Admin?
文职?
The government should compensate me.
你不如叫香港政府赔钱给我
But they won't.
叫他赔又不赔
I even need to pay for court fees.
还要我自已出钱打官司
Isn't it ridiculous?
你说有没有搞错?
You call this well arranged?
这样就叫安排好了吗?
I've done so much for the Force and for the citizens.
你说我为警队 为市民出了多少力?
What do I get in return?
我现在得到些什么?
If I go out now...
我现在上街
I dunno which roads
都不知道有多少路
are good for the crippled.
是给伤残人士走的!
All your buddies are waiting for you.
兄弟们都等你出去
Hang tough.
你为什么不撑下去呢?
I'm hanging tough.
我现在不就在撑吗?
If they're waiting for me, they'll pick me up here.
等我出来就来接我
But you're the only one.
就你一个?
I've left something. Don't wait for me.
我遗下了东西 你不要等我了
How are you?
你怎么样?
Tiger and I will be back before your trial.
大哥 我跟阿虎会在你上庭之前回来
I won't let Wilson and Sam testify.
我不会让华生和阿山有机会出庭作证
Tiger.
阿虎...
Mom.
妈
Three sons...
三个儿子...
I'll take you home.
我带你回家
Mom, you remember here?
妈 你记不记得这里?
We used to live here.
我们以前住过的
After I pick up Archer, we'll leave Hong Kong.
等我把哥哥接回来 就离开香港
Give it to me.
给我
- What so funny? - Nothing.
- 你笑什么? - 没什么
I rather like your foot injury.
我在想你的脚伤了也好
You won't be horsing around all day.
可以不用整天去玩
You can stay with me at home from now on.
以后都可以在家陪我
You took great care of me.
你照顾我这么久
You must love me deeply.
你是不是很喜欢我?
Don't you know that inside a woman's DNA,
你不知道女性的DNA里
there's a gene for taking care of others?
天生就有照顾人的因子吗?
For this gene,
为你这神圣的遗传因子
I'd rather stay like that forever.
我希望我一世都是这样
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
- 谢谢 - 别客气
They're here.
他们来了
Let me change my pants first. Be right there. - Be careful.
先换裤子 很快... 小心点
Hello! Delivery!
你好 送货的 收货啊
Hurry up!
喂 赶快吧
Hurry up! Come have a look. Great stuff!
快点过来看看 好东西
- What a heavy gift! - Definitely heavier than Inspector Wong.
- 这么贵重? - 一定比黄长官重!
Why you live on the top floor? It's so heavy.
你怎么住在天台 想累死人吗?
We're only giving a hand.
我们只是帮手搬
Ma is the greatest. He bought it and delivered it.
阿军最伟大 连搬带送
Where should we put it?
放在哪里?
Put it here.
放在哪里吧!
Give me a hand!
帮手!
- Stay out of the way! - Stay out of the way!
- 走开! - 你走开
Hurry up!
快点 快点
Slowly. Don't scratch it.
慢慢 慢慢 小心不要弄花
This chair costs 30 grand. Paid by one person only.
这张椅子三万多块钱 一个人负责
Sincere enough? That goes without saying.
够诚意了吧? 心照不宣
- Got an extension socket? - Yes.
- 有没有拖板? - 有
Let me do it. You guys are so clumsy.
等我来 你们粗手粗脚 真是的
Hurry up. Where's the extension socket?
快点 拖板呢?
I know you're poor in English. It's also in Chinese.
早知道你的英文不行 有中文的
Automatic. Just like driving a car.
好像开车一样 自动
Press this button.
你按这个键
You say your foot hurts all the time.
你成天说脚痛
This machine
我想这部机器
circulates the blood in your foot.
可以帮助你脚部血液循环
My blood is fine. I just can't walk with this foot.
我的血是流动的 不能动的是腿
Walking shouldn't be that difficult. Given your intelligence and wisdom.
想走路有多难? 以你的聪明才智
Train your left foot to be as dexterous as your right one.
将左脚练到好像右脚般灵活就行
- You know what you're talking about? - Just kidding.
- 你知道你自已说什么吗? - 开玩笑
But I guess the joke is dead. I'll stop laughing.
笑到咳嗽也没有人笑 不笑了
Let me open the door.
我去开
Delivery!
送外卖!
- Smells good! - It's food.
- 好香 - 吃东西
- What is it? - Good stuff.
- 什么来的? - 好东西
This family is most important to you.
其实你现在最紧要这个家
I envy you.
我很羡慕你
What's more important than family?
有什么紧要得过家
If you can be like me, you're blessed.
你好像我...就有福气了
Food is ready.
过来吃东西
Wait... Let's have a group pic first.
先等一下...大家拍张照再吃
Sure, we can take the pic while we eat.
好 一边吃一边拍
No, let's have the pic before we eat.
不行 先拍完再吃
I cooked this chicken for you.
这只鸡是我请大家吃的
- Have a pic with the chicken. - With the chicken?
- 跟鸡照相? - 跟鸡照相?
Go ahead. As a memento mori.
照 照张遗照 不介意吧
Good. Done!
好 行了
Let's plunge in.
吃吧...
- But the chicken is very cold. - Let's eat right away.
- 不过这只鸡很冷 - 对 吃吧...快点
Wait a minute.
等一下
Heat it up.
热一下就行
We have our standards.
做人没有追求 怎么能进步?
- Doesn't matter. We can still eat it. - Inspector Wong!
- 没所谓了 都可以吃 - 黄长官
Just put it in the oven. Very simple.
热一会就行...有多难?
Chicken... 200 degrees...
鸡...200度...
You shouldn't eat...
你不要吃...
I'll give Inspector Wong a hand.
我去帮黄长官
Is Judy all right?
嫂子没事吧?
She's still in the observation ward.
留院观察
Are you guys OK?
你们没事吧?
I'm officially taking over Inspector Wong's duties.
我现在正式接替黄长官
To play safe, the whole team will take a vacation.
为安全起见 你们全组放假
They're trying to kill a cop and a witness.
现在杀警察 杀证人
It has to be the Viets.
傻瓜都知道是那班越南人做的
Why a vacation?
还放假?
I'm concerned about your safety.
我担心你们会有危险
Everyone is risking his life.
同事都为我们卖命
You want us to lay off?
你一上来就叫我们不干?
You're in Admin now. Go first.
你现在调了文职 先出去
When I was a snitch, I was scared every day.
我做卧底时 每天惶惶不可终日
Now that I'm crippled, I should be better off.
我以为现在跛了 有好日子过了
Even my house was bombed.
就连房子都给炸掉
You want me to go?
我出去?
Madam, the uniform is not for showing off.
长官 制服不是用来炫耀的
I'll bust them if we have enough evidence.
有足够证据 我会去抓人
Do we?
你有证据吗?
Look what the Madam is doing!
你们看看长官有什么要做
Where is Tony?
Tony在哪?
I dunno.
不知道...
Enough. You're killing him.
够了 你打死他了
Give me the gun... Give me the gun!
把枪给我...把枪给我!
Give me the gun!
把枪给我!
- Give the gun! - He dunno.
- 把枪给我! - 他不知道的
You're going to court tomorrow.
你明天都上庭了
Madam, what should we do now?
长官 现在如何?
It's most important to find out where Tony is.
现在最重要是知道Tony的下落
It's most important to protect Wilson in the hospital.
现在最重要是去医院保住华生
He's the only witness left.
他是唯一证人
Let's go, Cindy.
走吧 小樱
Let's go, Yang. Still writing!
走吧 杨仔 还写什么!
I prefer the old you. Don't be a cop.
我宁愿你好像从前一样 不要做警察
You're crazy...
神经病...
Mom has a house back home.
妈妈在乡下有一间屋
Let's live with her.
我想回去跟她同住
You hate it here?
你很讨厌这里吗?
I've been here for long,
其实来了香港这么久
but it never feels like home.
都不觉得这里是家
Mom wants the three...
妈妈说想我们回去
of us to go back.
想我们三个人回去
Already two months.
已经两个月了
You don't like it?
你不喜欢?
Frisk everyone in and out of the hospital.
出入医院的人全部都要搜身
Every entrance and exit, back door,
所有出口 门口 后门
stairwell, toilet...
后楼梯 洗手间
Everywhere. ls that clear?
全部都要有人 清楚吗?
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
The trial is about to start. Wilson has to be OK.
一会便要出庭 华生一定不能有事
He's hungry.
他肚子饿了
Should we buy him some food?
要不要买东西给他吃
I'll buy you something to eat!
我买东西回来给你吃吧!
Don't run around.
你记得不要乱跑
Wait, Inspector Ma.
马长官 等一下
Wilson, Inspector Ma asked you not to run around.
华生哥 马长官叫你不要乱跑
Thanks!
谢谢!
Police! Stay away!
警察办案 让开 让开!
There're gunshots at the elevator hallway.
电梯大堂有枪声
The suspect is in the elevator. Get help! Fast!
疑犯乘电梯上楼 找人来帮忙 快点
I have her...
她在我这儿...
OK...
行...
What do you want? Just say it! I'll do it.
你想怎么样? 说? 什么都行
Are you scared?
你很怕吗?
Yes...Yes...
对...对...
What do you want?
你想...说...你想怎么样?
Just say it! I'll do it.
说...什么都行!
Watch out! Wanna die?
小心啊 找死吗?
Go!
走!
Mommy!
妈妈
Toss me your weapon.
把枪抛过来
Put the girl down!
放下那个女孩!
I said toss me your weapon!
我叫你把枪抛过来!
Give me back my daughter!
把女儿还给我!
I'll blow her head off!
我撞破她的头!
- Put the girl down! - You want her dead?
- 放下那女孩! - 你是不是想她死!
How are you, darling?
女儿 你怎么样?
Answer me!
你应我一下!
Inspector Ma? What's the situation?
马长官? 情况如何?
Inspector Ma!
马长官!
Gotta go to court!
到时间上法庭了
Hello...
喂...
Wilson, where are you?
华生 你在哪?
Off to the court!
正在去法庭
Something happened to Judy?
嫂子 是不是出了事?
Yes!
是!
Don't believe him. He won't let her go.
你不要信他 他不会放过嫂子
I got no choice!
我没有选择!
Why not?
你怎么会没有选择?
You're choosing to help the bastards.
你现在选了帮那班混蛋
I don't want anything to happen to her.
我不想她有事
I don't want anything to happen to either of you.
我不想你们俩有事
You wanna die with her?!
你是不是要抱着女朋友一块死?
I need a statement from you.
你要录一份口供
You killed the suspect.
那犯人给你打死了
Arrest me then.
那你抓我吧
Witness, you can testify now.
证人 你可以作供
I don't remember anything.
我什么都不记得了
Because the witness failed to testify
本席宣判 证人以失忆为理由
for loss of memory,
未能作供
the court rules that all charges against Archer Sin
对于疑犯冼伟查的一切控罪
shall be dismissed for lack of evidence.
由于证据不足 当庭释放
Tony, I'm out.
Tony 我出来了
Speak! Where?
说话! 在哪?
Nan Shang Wei.
南生围
Hurry up. I'll wait for you.
你快点来 我等你
Stop fighting. Stop it!
不要打...停手
Stop fighting...
不要打...
Wilson...
华生...
Wilson..
I never thought I would leave...
我没有想过我可以走...
I just want her to be OK...
我只是想她没有事...
Wilson...
华生...
Shoot! Shoot, Tony!
开枪 开枪 开枪啊 Tony
Go ahead! Scared?
来吧 害怕吗!
Drop your piece!
把枪放下!
- Drop your piece! - Drop your motherfucker!
- 把枪放下! - 放你老娘!
- Asshole! - Shoot! What you waiting for?
- 混蛋! - 开枪吧 干什么!
Don't curse my mom!
别再说我妈!
Bro!
哥!
Shoot the asshole!
射死你这王八蛋
Shit!
老妈米
Let me drive.
让我开车
Open the door, what do you want?
开门 你想怎么样?
Open the door, what's the matter?
开门啊 干什么?
Come with me. Don't go back.
跟我走 不要回去
Don't go. You promised me you wouldn't go.
不要走 你答应过我不去的
Ma, come out and fight me.
马军 出来单挑!
Shit!
老妈米
Kenji
Kenji啊
You're over, Tony.
你玩完了 Tony
Have I ever busted the wrong guy?
我当警察这么久有没有抓错人?
I'll leave the answer to the judge.
这个答案留给法官回答
My duty as a cop...
我的职责是...
Is to catch thieves.
警察抓贼